Guide to the Belva Kibler and Donald Morgan Collection
Stanford Archive of Recorded Sound
Belva Kibler and Donald Morgan Collection
1926-1995
ARS-0009
Belva Kibler
Donald Morgan
14? (23 boxes, 1 poster tube)
Stanford Archive of Recorded Sound Stanford University Libraries Stanford, California 94305-3076
The Kibler-Morgan collection contains their annotated scores, photographs, programs, scrapbooks, correspondence, newspaper clippings, books and recordings.
Access
Collection is open for research. Listening appointments may require 24 hours notice. Contact the Archive Operations Manager.
Biography / Administrative History
The mezzo-soprano Belva Kibler (1914-1983), was born in California and trained at the Cincinnati Conservatory. Her early appearances in Los Angeles included the West Coast premiere of Prokofieff?s Alexander Nevsky under the baton of Otto Klemperer. In New York she was consistently successful as a soloist with Arthur Mendel?s Cantata Singers with whom she performed Bach?s St. Mathew and St. John Passions, the Christmas Oratorio and the Mass in B minor. In 1951 she undertook a recital tour through Germany and Austria, and was very favorably received. Kibler was the chosen performer for several productions of contemporary works such as Benjamin Britten?s Rape of Lucretia in which she sang the coveted role of Lucretia for the American premiere and as Ann in Virgil Thomson?s Mother of us all. She also appeared in the film of Gian Carlo Menotti?s The Medium as Mrs. Gobineau and performed and recorded Schoenberg?s F?nfzehn Gedichte aus Das Buch der h?ngenden G?rten.
The bass-baritone Donald Morgan was born in Pomona, California in 1911. After receiving his B.A. degree from Stanford University (1933) he embarked on five years of graduate study in German literature and combined it with singing lessons at the universities of Cologne, Bonn and Munich. Back in the US he became a German professor at the University of Minnesota. He continued his musical career by doing solo work with the University?s Bach Society and the St. Paul Opera Company. The latter?s production of Smetana?s Bartered Bride led to an invitation to sing in Brahms? Requiem with the Minneapolis Symphony Orchestra under Dimitri Mitropoulos. Shortly after Pearl Harbor, Morgan responded to a call from the War Department to do censorship work in Florida, Puerto Rico and England. Later he was transferred to the U.S Military Government in Germany where he was engaged in post-war work with the industrial leaders of Germany. During those years he gave many performances for the German public and the U.S. Armed Forces. In 1949 he was invited by the British Goethe Festival Society in London to perform a concert of Goethe songs. A year later he was chosen for the role of Mr. Gobineau in Menotti?s The Medium. The tragic opera was filmed in Rome with Menotti as composer, director and writer. Donald Morgan and Belva Kibler met during The Medium?s filming, and married shortly thereafter. Morgan died in 1995.
Scope and Content of Collection
The collection?s largest component consists of scores. The most interesting being the special Bach renditions of Belva Kibler under Arthur Mendel, and eight vocal manuscripts by Mario Castelnuovo Tedesco, two of which are dedicated to Belva Kibler. Among the photographs of Kibler and Morgan on stage there is an extensive set of photos from the filming of Menotti?s The Medium. Their collection of programs dates from 1926 to 1971. Most of the publications and documents deal with the US involvement in the reconstruction of Germany?s industry after the war. Among the newspaper clippings there is a set of reviews of Kibler?s recital tour of Germany and Austria in 1951.
Arrangement
1. Personal documents; 2. Correspondence; 3. Photographs; 4. Programs; 5. Opera materials; 6. Publications; 7. Documents; 8. Scrapbooks; 9. Newspaper clippings; 10. Books; 11. Scores; 12. Music manuscripts; 13. Pedagogical materials; 14. Recordings; 15. Posters; 16. Miscellaneous.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Kibler, Belva; Morgan, Donald; Vocal music
Container List
- Biography, Kibler (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Biography, Morgan (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Medical records, Kibler (Box 1, Folder 3)
- German documents, Morgan (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Morgan's inventory of collection (Box 1, Folder 5)
- 1931-1933, Kibler (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 1949 -1956, Kibler (Box 1, Folder 2)
- 1933 -1947, Morgan (Box 1, Folder 3)
- 1938 -1954, Morgan (Box 1, Folder 4)
- 1972 - 79, Kibler and Morgan (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Letter to Mrs. Charles Chaplin from Dr. John Vincent and autograph by Aaron CoplandDec. 10, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Promotional portraits, Kibler (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Menotti, Gian Carlo, 1911-2007. Medium. Kibler and Morgan (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Trovatore. Kibler as Azucena (Box 1, Folder 4)
- On stage. Kibler (Box 1, Folder 5)
- With other musicians. Kibler (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Social functions. Kibler (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Portraits. Morgan (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Cosi` fan tutte. Morgan (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Set of photographs, possibly Germany. Morgan (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Morgan as postwar supervisor, Germany. (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Kibler and Morgan (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Heiberg, Harold, pianist (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Britten, Benjamin, 1913-1976. Rape of Lucretia. Kibler (Oversize 4, Folder 2)
- 1926 - 1932 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- 1933 - 1939 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- 1941 - 1947 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- 1947 - 1948 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Salzburger Festspiele 1947, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- 1949 - 1951 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- 1951- 1953 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- 1953- 1954 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- 1955- 1960 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- 1960 - 1971 and undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Leoncavallo, Ruggiero, 1858-1919. Pagliacci. Libretto (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Bender, Paul, 1875-1947 materials (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Menotti, Gian Carlo, 1911-2007. Medium. (Box 5, Folder 3)
  Publication on the film
- Menotti, Gian Carlo, 1911-2007. Medium. (Box 5, Folder 4)
  Synopsis and shooting script
- Opera Quarterly, Vol 3, #2, summer 1985 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  Film review. Menotti, Gian Carlo, 1911-2007. Medium.
- Sydney Opera House (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Magie der Oper (Oversize 4, Folder 7)
- Opera Cavalcade. Story of the Metropolitan (Oversize 4, Folder 8)
- Cultural (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Historical, San Francisco (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Travel, Germany (1937-38) (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Etude, 1904 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Historical. Germany 1930s (Box 6, Folder 5)
- München im Bild. Die Sammlung Parthenon (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Religious (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Pioneers of the Science of Chemistry (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Business (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Application forms. Munich University 1930s (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Military1947 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Application for Federal Employment1947 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Political. Nazi propaganda1933 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Political. Nazi propaganda1933 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Press transcripts (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Black binder scrapbook 1935 - 1952, 17 1/2" x15 1/2" (Box 7, Folder 1)
  Programs, photographs, clippings
- Beige, natural-matrerial covers scrapbook and encasing with flower pattern, 10 3/4" x 9 1/4" (Box 7, Folder 2)
  One inscription "This came from a Robert Browning letter at Trinity College, Dublin. I thought of you: 'You say that you are fond of singing. Nothing, then could be more appropriate than that you cultivate the art. It is a difficult one, to be sure, else where would lie the merit in mastering it?' Chris. Munich Germany. 19 October, 1949 -- Two Morgan programs, 1947 and 1949
- Brown covers with green leaves Scrapbook. With lettering: Photographs 1945 - 1958, 10 1/4" x 12 3/4" (Box 8, Folder 3)
  Photographs, programs, clippings, correspondence
- 1930 - 1945 (Oversize 4, Folder 1)
- 1947 - 1951 (Oversize 4, Folder 2)
- 1952 - 1959 (Oversize 4, Folder 3)
- Annotated books (Box 9)
  Avenarius, Ferdinand, ed. Hausbuch Deutscher Lyrik -- Bergen, Franz. Versungen und Vertan? Ein Mahnwort an alle, die Saenger werden wollen -- Burk, John N. Clara Schumann -- Caruso, Enrico. Wie man singen soll! -- Darrell, R. Compiler. Gramaphone Shop. Encyclopedia of recorded music -- Elson, Arthur. Book of Musical Knowledge -- Balch Nevin, Gordon. A Primer of Organ. Registration -- Cardus, Neville, ed. Kathleen Ferrier. A Memoir -- Furtwängler, Wilhelm. Gespräche über Musik --Lavignac, Albert. Music Dramas of Richard Wagner -- Lehmann, Lotte. More than Singing -- Leighton, George. A. Harmony. Analytical and Applied -- Meyer, Hermann. Richtig denken - richtig singen -- Paumgartner, B. Mozart -- Riemann, Hugo. Handbuch des Musik-Diktats -- Rutz, Hans. Schubert. Dokumente seines Lebens und Schaffens -- Schiedermair, Ludwig. Musikalische Begegnungen -- Stillman Kelley, Edgar. Musical Instruments -- Volbach, Fritz. Kunst der Sprache. Uebungsband -- Wagenmann. Umsturz in der Stimmbildung; Enrico Caruso und das Problem der Stimmbildung -- Walter, Bruno. Thema und Variationen. Erinnerungen und Gedanken von Bruno Walter --
- Adams - Bach (Box 10)
  Adams, Stephen. Holy City -- Allitsen, Frances, 1848-1912. Like as the hart desireth -- Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Matthäuspassion (five different editions); Johannespassion (two different editions); Mass, S. 232, B minor (two different editions)
- Bach - Brahms (Box 11)
  Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Weihnachts-Oratorium (two different editions); Magnificat, BWV 243, D major; Mein Gott, wie lang', ach lange; Fünfzehn Arien für eine Bassstimme aus Kantaten; Ich will den Kreuzstab gerne tragen; Ich freue mich in dir (aria); Bist du bei mir; Gedenke doch mein Geist zurücke; Songs & Airs for contralto -- Barber, Samuel, 1910-1981. Songs, op. 10. I hear an army; Hand of bridge -- Barker, Clement W. If we live in the spirit; Woe unto the foolish prophets -- Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827. An die freude; Sämtliche Lieder -- Bizet, Georges, 1838-1875. Arlésienne. Intermezzo; arr.; Carmen. Chanson du toréador -- Bohm, Carl, 1844-1920. Lieder, op. 326. Still wie die Nacht (three different editions) -- Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897. Lieder; Deutsches Requiem; Zigeunerlieder, op. 103; Gesänge, op. 71. An den Mond; Rhapsodies, alto, men's voices, orchestra, op. 53; Gesänge, viola, piano acc., op. 91. Gestillte Sehnsucht; Geistliches Wiegenlied (two copies); Ernste Gesänge (three copies, two different editons)
- Bridge - Guion (Box 12)
  Bridge, Frank, 1879-1941. Love went a-riding -- Brown, Russell J. Father, thou who art in heav'n -- Buck, Dudley, 1839-1909. Studies in pedal phrasing for the organ; My redeemer an dmy Lord; Salve Regina; Hear not ye, O Israel -- Bush, Grace. Ave Maria -- Charles, Ernest, 1895-1984. Sweet song of long ago -- Cimara, Pietro. Fiocco la neve -- Coward, Noel, 1899-1973. Bitter-sweet. Zigeuner -- Cui, César, 1835-1918. Trois oiseaux -- Donizetti, Gaetano, 1797-1848. Lucrezia Borgia; Maria di Rohan. Per non istare in ozio -- Dvorák, Antonín, 1841-1904. Zigeunermelodien; Goin 'home -- Dubois, Théodore, 1837-1924. Sept paroles du Christ -- Eayrs, M. P. Salve Regina -- Falla, Manuel de, 1876-1946. Canciones populares españolas -- Fauré, Gabriel, 1845-1924. Vocal selections -- Franck, César, 1822-1890. Panis angelicus (three copies, two different editions) -- Flotow, Friedrich von, 1812-1883. Martha -- Gabrieli, Andrea, ca. 1533-1585. Magnificat -- Gabrieli, Giovanni, 1557-1612. Symphoniae sacrae. Jubilate Deo -- Galbraith, Lamont J. Thine is the Greatness -- Gluck, Christoph Willibald, Ritter von, 1714-1787. "O Saviour, hear me!" Offertory for alto -- Gounod, Charles, 1818-1893. Ave Maria (Vocal version); O divine redeemer; Entreat me not to leave thee; There is a green hill far away; Faust; Avant de quitter ces lieux -- Guion, David W. (David Wendell), 1892-1981. Prayer; At the cry of the first bird
- Hamblen - Loewe (Box 13)
  Hamblen, Bernard. Beside still waters -- Handel, George Frideric, 1685-1759. Semele. Where'er you walk; Radamisto, HWV 12a. Selections; Xerxes; Messiah (two editions); Israel in Egypt -- Harker, Flaxington F. Blest are the pure in heart; O Love that wilt not let me go; How beautiful upon the mountains -- Hay Malotte, Albert. Beatitudes -- Haydn, Joseph, 1732-1809. Sieben letzten Worte unseres Erlösers am Kreuze; Schöpfung (two different editions) -- Hummel, Ferdinand, 1855-1928. Halleluja -- Humphreys, Donald Edwin, 1891-. When I consider thy heavens -- Kerby, Paul. Oh, to be in England. (With dedication by composer) -- Kilpinen, Yrjö. Lieder -- Korngold, Erich Wolfgang, 1897-1957. Tote Stadt. Selections; Einfache Lieder. Liebesbriefchen -- De Koven, Reginald, 1859-1920. Poppies. Slumber song -- Brandl, Johann, 1835-1913. Liebe Augustin. Du alter Stefansturm; arr. by Kreisler, Fritz (two copies) -- Lacy, Della. Teach me to know -- La Forge, Frank, 1879-1953. Dinanzi al Crocifisso -- Lehmann, Liza, 1862-1918. In a Persian garden -- Lemare, Edwin H. (Edwin Henry), 1865-1934. Pastorale -- Leoni, Franco, 1864-1949. Tally - Ho! -- Liddle, Samuel, 1868-1935?. How lovely are thy dwellings -- Loewe, Carl, 1796-1869. Album (two volumes)
- Lortzing - Mozart (Box 14)
  Lortzing, Albert, 1801-1851. Waffenschmied -- MacDermid, James G., 1875-1960. Shepherd, show me how to go; Mother's evening prayer -- For the mountains shall depart -- Mahler, Gustav, 1860-1911. Lieder eines fahrenden Gesellen -- Malashkin, L. D. O, esli-by mog vyrazit' -- Marx, Joseph, 1882-1964. Regenlied; Lieder und Gesänge. Marienlied -- Massenet, Jules, 1842-1912. Werther -- Mendelssohn, Arnold, 1855-1933. Aus dem Nachtlied Zarathustras -- Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, 1809-1847. Elias; Paulus -- Menotti, Gian Carlo, 1911-2007. Consul -- Meyerbeer, Giacomo, 1791-1864. Huguenots. Selections -- Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Ave verum corpus; Nicotra, Tobia. Baci amorosi e cari; Così fan tutte; Zauberflöte
- Mozart - Saint Saëns (Box 15)
  Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Zauberflöte; Entführung aus dem Serail -- O' Connor - Morris, G. Alleluia! -- O' Hara, Geoffrey. I love a little cottage (with dedication by poet Stott Gilmore, Roscoe; Living God -- Ponchielli, Amilcare, 1834-1886. Gioconda -- Puccini, Giacomo, 1858-1924. Madama Butterfly -- -- Purcell, Henry, 1659-1695. Dido and Aeneas. When I am laid in earth -- Rachmaninoff, Sergei, 1873-1943. Romansy, op. 4. V molchani nochi tainoi -- Ravel, Maurice, 1875-1937. Chansons, mixed voices. Nicolette -- Reilly, J. A., O Lord I am not worthy -- Rhené - Baton. Nuit d' autrefois -- Rogers, Clara Kathleen, 1844-1931. Songs -- Rogers, James H. (James Hotchkiss), 1857-1940. Prayer -- Roof, Frederic W. O'er waiting harpstrings of the mind -- Shelley, Harry Rowe, 1858-1947. Ave Maria -- Sachs, Henry. Dream Ships -- Saint-Saëns, Camille, 1835-1921. Samson et Dalila (two different editions)
- Sanderson - Strauss (Box 16)
  Sanderson, W. (Wilfred). Until -- Schoenberg, Arnold, 1874-1951. Buch der hängenden Gärten -- Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Winterreise. Vocal part only; An die Musik; Sammlung der Lieder -- Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856. Frauenliebe und Leben; Sämtliche Lieder (volumes II and III. Vol. I of a different edition); Schütz, Heinrich, 1585-1672. Historia der Auferstehung Jesu Christi; Psalmen Davids (1619) 98. Psalm; Psalmen Davids (1619). 100. Psalm; Musicalische Exequien -- Scott, Charles P. (Charles Phillips), 1868-1926. God is a spirit -- Scott, John Prindle, 1877-1932. Consider the Lilies; They that trust in the Lord -- Secchi, Benedetto. Lungi dal caro bene -- Wright, Norman. Twenty-Third Psalm -- Spross, Charles Gilbert. Come ye to the mountains of the Lord -- Stainer, J. F. R. (John Frederick Randall), 1866-1939. Crucifixion -- Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Lieder, op. 10. Allerseelen; Zueignung
- Strauss - True (Box 17)
  Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Rosenkavalier -- Tate, Arthur F. Somewhere a voice is calling -- Tchaikovsky, Peter Ilich, 1840-1893. Dans le tourbillon du bal -- Thomas, Ambroise, 1811-1896. Mignon -- Tourjee, Homer. Comforter -- Trunk, Richard. Vier Gesänge -- True, Latham, 1874-1945. Christmastide; Grow old along with me; Browning Songs (with dedication by composer); Valley of the shadow; Into the wood I took my grief (with dedication by composer); Our day with thee (with dedication by composer); Mater Adorans (with dedication by composer); Song Etchings; Sorrow; Afterward; Ere time began; Jean; Three German miniatures; Holy lamp; Canticle of Pan; Song of the sea; Fragrance of the dusk; Portrait; Abt Vogler; Young King; Riders to the sea; Hound of Heaven; Lyric Sketches; Song Pastels; Lyric Improvisations (with dedication by composer); Castilleja Sonata for organ; Tone paintings for organ and piano; Evensong; Serious songs; Song miniatures (with dedication by composer); Fragrance of Dusk
- Vaccai - Zeizl and Compilations (Box 18)
  Vaccai, Nicola, 1790-1848. Practical method -- Van Dyke, May. As a shepherd; God is a spirit -- Vaughan Williams, Ralph, 1872-1958. House of life. Silent noon -- Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Messa da Requiem (two different editions); Don Carlos. Elle ne m'aime pas; Vèpres siciliennes -- Webb, Jane M. U. Lonely (with dedication) -- Wolf, Hugo, 1860-1903. Italienisches Liederbuch; Lieder collectiion; Michelangelo-Lieder; Freund -- Yon, Pietro A., 1886-1943. Gesù bambino (two different editions) -- Young, W. Ernest (Walter Ernest), 1887-. Christmas Morn -- Zeizl, Erich. Kinder Lieder -- Compilations: Italian songs -- Sacred songs -- Kücken -- Arias for bass
- Compilations and Methods (Box 19)
  American folk songs -- French songs -- German songs -- Liederkranz -- Deutscher Liederschatz -- Italian airs -- Russian songs -- Spanish folk songs -- Negro spirituals -- Christmas songs -- Singing method (title page missing) -- Lohmann, Paul. Das Lied im Unterricht -- Carl, William C. Thirty postludes for the organ -- Photocopies of annotated pages of various scores
- Kibler's collection of songs I, Black hard covers 6 1/2'' x 5 1/2''. Pages held by elastic strings. (Box 8, Folder 17)
  Vocal parts only
- Kibler's collection of songs II, Black hard covers 6 1/2'' x 5 1/2''. Pages held by elastic strings. (Box 8, Folder 18)
- Kibler's collection of songs III, Brown ring binder 6'' x 4''. Gold lettering on covers: Belva L. Kibler Contralto (Box 8, Folder 19)
- Bush, Grace. Pleading (Box 20, Folder 2)
- Castelnuovo-Tedesco, Mario, 1895-1968. Shakespeare Sonnets 1945, Photocopy (Box 20, Folder 3)
  XXXI All Hearts; LXXIII Yellow Leaves; XC; CXXVIII Harpsichord; CXLVI. Dedication on two of the photocopies of Tedesco's manuscripts, In Sonnet XC "To Belva Kibler this Sonnet which was meant for her. Mario Castelnuovo-Tedesco"; In Sonnet CXLVI "To Belva Kibler who first sang this Sonnet for me. With friendship and admiration. Mario Castelnuovo Tedesco.
- Castelnuovo-Tedesco, Mario, 1895-1968. De Amico ad Amicam1947, Photocopy (Box 20, Folder 4)
  (Text from a love letter c. 1300)
- Castelnuovo-Tedesco, Mario, 1895-1968. Songs, Photocopy (Box 20, Folder 5)
  Two Byron Songs (1941); Three Sephardic Songs (1949)
- Heidemann, Hans. Mondlicht, Photocopy (Box 20, Folder 6)
  Text by Theodor Storm
- Korngold, Erich Wolfgang, 1897-1957. Constant Nymph. Tessa's Song, Mimiographed copy of ms with pink pencil markings (Box 20, Folder 7)
- Leinert, Friedrich, 1908-. Tristesse de la lune, Original ms by composer (Box 20, Folder 8)
  "To Belva Kibler with best wishes Dr. F. Leinert. 25. II. 51 Marburg/L Germany.
- Mc Clearly, Fiona. Songs, Original ms by composer (Box 20, Folder 9)
  Old Woman; Prière; Mary Stuart's prayer; Quality of love; Rainer Maria Rilke song settings; Si j' étais dieu; While I seek you far-away
- Rózsa, Miklós, 1907-1995. Songs, Photocopy (Box 20, Folder 10)
  Beasts of Burden; Invocation
- Schütz, Heinrich, 1585-1672. Kleine geistliche Concerte.1951 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  Edited and copyright by Arthur Mendel
- Stephani, Hermann. Songs, Photocopies (Box 20, Folder 12)
  Abendstern; Alte Wunder; Einmal werden wir im Lichte wandeln; Erkenntnis; Flüchtlingslos; Frühling; Gang durch die Felder; Heimat; Holde Mai; Kind zur Weihnacht; Im Walde; In der Frühe; In die Ferne; Inneres Licht; Kleiner Ton; Oever de stillen Straten; O schweigen; Pflügunter; Rhapsoden; Stunde der Nacht; Wir harren; Wohl unter der grünen Linde
- True, Latham, 1874-1945, Original ms by composer (Box 20, Folder 13)
  Symphony Suite: Castilleja III. Ballad. Signed by composer, and dated May 30, 1931 -- Abendlied. Signed by composer and dated Aug. 1938
- Wirtz, Warren. Songs, Photocopies (Box 20, Folder 14)
  Three Settings of Gerard Marley Hopkins' Pied Beauty (Dec. 8, 1949); Three Songs on Poems by W. B. Yeats (May 25, 1951). Card by composer "Dear Miss Kibler, I'm sending some songs on to you and hope you'll like them..." Oct. 23, 1952
- Miscellaneous sacred vocal pieces (Box 20, Folder 15)
  Mostly copied by Belva Kibler
- Unidentified vocal pieces (Box 20, Folder 16)
- Leaf from a Medieval chant book (Oversize 4, Folder 1)
- Kibler's Cincinnati Conservatory materials (Oversize 4, Folder 1)
- French Pronunciation Manual by Nicole Cardos (Oversize 4, Folder 2)
- Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Matthäuspassion 1-34 (Othertype 21, Folder 1)
  Troxell, Barbara, soprano; Carter, Sara, soprano; Kibler, Belva, 1913-1983, alto; Hess, William, tenor; Williams, Brent, tenor; Warfield, William, tenor; Matthen, Paul, bass
- Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Matthäuspassion 1-34 (Othertype 21, Folder 2)
- Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Matthäuspassion 1-34 (Othertype 21, Folder 3)
- Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Matthäuspassion 1-34 (Othertype 21, Folder 4)
- Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Matthäuspassion 35-66 (Othertype 21, Folder 5)
- Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Matthäuspassion 35-66 (Othertype 21, Folder 6)
- Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Matthäuspassion 35-66 (Othertype 21, Folder 7)
- Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Matthäuspassion 35-66 (Othertype 21, Folder 8)
- Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Matthäuspassion 67-78; Lobet Gott in seinen Reichen (Othertype 21, Folder 9)
- Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Matthäuspassion 67-78 (Othertype 21, Folder 10)
- Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Matthäuspassion 67-78 (Othertype 21, Folder 11)
- Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Matthäuspassion 67-78 (Othertype 21, Folder 12)
- Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Matthäuspassion 67-78 (Othertype 21, Folder 13)
- Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Johannespassion 1-52 (Othertype 21, Folder 14)
  Curtin, Phyllis, soprano; Kibler, Belva, 1913-1983, alto; Hess, William, tenor; Brock, Karl, tenor; Matthen, Paul, bass; Warfield, William, bass
- Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Johannespassion 53-68 (Othertype 21, Folder 15)
- Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Mass in B minor 1-15 (Othertype 21, Folder 16)
  Faull, Ellen, soprano; Kibler, Belva, 1913-1983, alto; Williams, Brent, tenor; Matthen, Paul, bass
- Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Mass in B minor 16-23 (Othertype 21, Folder 17)
  Mass in B minor. Faull, Ellen, soprano; Kibler, Belva, 1913-1983, alto; Williams, Brent, tenor; Matthen, Paul, bass; Schauet doch und sehet, ob irgend ein Schmerz sei; Gott, man lobet dich in der Stille; Bloecher, Charlotte, soprano; Kibler, Belva, 1913-1983, alto; Hess, William; Matthen, Paul, bass
- Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. (Othertype 22, Folder 18)
  Magnificat, BWV 243, D major; Weinen, Klagen, Sorgen, Zagen
- Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Arias (Othertype 22, Folder 19)
  Ferrier, Kathleen, 1912-1953, contralto
- Mahler, Gustav, 1860-1911. Klagende Lied (Othertype 22, Folder 20)
  Falcon, Ruth, soprano; Quivar, Florence, mezzo-soprano; Jenkins, Timothy, tenor; Gardner, Jake, baritone. New York Philharmonic. Colon, James, conductor.
- Menotti, Gian Carlo, 1911-2007. MediumFeb. 15, 1959 (Othertype 22, Folder 21)
  Omnibus